Register of the National Republic records, 1918-1960
Hoover Institution Archives
- Information File A (Boxes 1-398)
  - Communist cultural activities
    - State movements (Box 106)
      - New Jersey
      - Oregon
      - Wisconsin
    - Organizations
    - Elections, radical votes
    - Propaganda, Congressional hearings [2 folders]
    - Film, plays (Box 107)
    - Theaters, motion pictures
  - Communist schools
    - General
    - Abraham Lincoln School
    - Jefferson School of Social Science
    - Affiliated Schools for Workers, Inc.
    - California Labor School
    - Pacific Northwest Labor School (Seattle Labor School) (Box 108)
    - School of Jewish Studies
    - Tom Mooney Labor School
    - New York Workers' School
    - People's Educational Center
    - Philadelphia School of Social Science and Art
    - Communist Workers School
    - American Youth for Democracy (Box 109)
    - Labor Youth League
    - Young Communist League (see also Labor Youth League and American Youth for Democracy)
    - Young Communist League [2 folders] (Box 110)
    - Communist activities - youth (Box 111)
    - General [2 folders]
    - Photostat exhibits
    - Communist Youth League
    - Young Circle League of America
    - Young Communist International
    - Young Pioneers of America
    - Crown Heights Labor School (Box 112)
    - Communist Teachers School
    - Communist Party Summer School in San Francisco
    - Downtown Community School
    - Documentary Film School
    - Downtown Music School
    - Federation of Children's Organizations
    - George Washington Carver School
    - John Reed Club School of Art
    - Lincoln House (Cleveland, Ohio)
    - Los Angeles Education Center
    - Los Angeles Workers School
    - Los Angeles Committees of Correspondence
    - Marx-Lenin School
    - Marxist School
    - Marxist Day School
    - Mohegan Colony School
    - National Training School of the Communist Party
    - New Jersey Labor School
    - New School
    - New Theater School
    - Oakland Labor School and People's Education Center
    - Ohio School of Social Sciences
    - Photo League School
    - Progressive Labor School of Boston
    - Robert Louis Stevenson School
    - Russian Government Schools in U.S. and Russia
    - Russian Federation's Schools
    - Samuel Adams School of Social Studies
    - San Francisco Labor School
    - School on Wheels
    - School of Stage for Action
    - School for Democracy
    - Seattle Communist College
    - Southern New Theater School
    - Summer School for Office Workers
    - Walt Whitman School
    - Washington School for Social Studies (Washington, D.C.?)
    - Workers Training School
    - Work People's College
    - San Antonio School
    - Nelson Davis Education Forum
    - Pittsburgh Communist School
    - Young Communist League Training School of New England
    - I.W.O. Aviation Club
    - Eva Shafran Educational Foundation
    - Peter Cacchione Training School, Washington, D.C.
    - Workers' Schools (in Chicago)
    - Cleveland Workers' School
    - Los Angeles Workers' School
    - Workers Schools' (in New York)
    - San Francisco Workers' School
    - Washington Workers' School (District of Columbia)
    - Pacific Coast Workers' Summer School
    - Philadelphia Workers' School
    - Pittsburgh Workers' School
  - Codes
  - Co, miscellaneous
  - Comics (Box 113)
  - Comments on subversive movements
  - Commerce, foreign and domestic
  - Commerce, Department of
  - Comment, adverse
  - Commission on Interracial Cooperation
  - Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy (National Republic)
  - Committee for Citizenship Rights
  - Committee for Economic Development
  - Committee for Constitutional Government
  - Committee for Constitutional Government (Box 114)
  - Committee for Economic Stability
  - Committee for National Morale
  - Committee for People's Rights
  - Committee for Racial Democracy in the Nation's Capital
  - Committee for Medical Freedom (See Independent Citizens Committee)
  - Committee for the Nation
  - Committee of Americans
  - Committee of Catholics for Human Rights
  - Committee of 48
  - Committee of One Thousand
  - Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin-America
  - Committee on Militarism in Education (Anti-ROTC and Training)
  - Committee for Protection of Foreign Born (See American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born)
  - Common Cause
  - Common Sense
  - Commonwealth Builders
  - Committee to Defend American by Aiding the Allies (Box 115)
  - Common Council for American Unity
  - Commonwealth Club of California
  - Com, miscellaneous
    - General
    - Pamphlets
  - Condon, Dr. Edward U. (Box 116)
  - Conference for Progressive Labor Action
  - Conference for Progressive Political Action
  - Conference on Democracy in Education
  - Congregational Education Society
  - Congress on Education for Democracy
  - Congressional Action
  - Congressional Intelligence
  - Conscientious Objectors
  - Constitution (Box 117)
    - General [4 folders]
    - Annotated (Red Folder) (Box 118)
    - Proposed amendments
    - Clippings
    - Addresses on (Box 119)
    - Literature
    - Educational League [2 folders]
    - Protective League of Kentucky
  - Consultative Pact
  - National Consumers' League
  - Consumers' Union of U.S.
  - Consumers' groups (Box 120)
  - Consumers' Research Inc.
  - Cooperatives
  - Continental Congress for Economic Reconstruction
  - Coolidge, Calvin
  - Cooper, Col. Hugh L.
  - Cooper Union
  - Cooperatives
    - Clippings
    - Farm
    - Foreign countries (Box 121)
    - Cooperative League
    - Farm
    - General
      - Pamphlets
      - Literature (Box 122)
    - National Association
  - Coordinating Committee of American-Polish Associations in the East
  - Costigan, Edward P.
  - Council Against Intolerance in America
  - Council for Pan-American Democracy
  - Coplon, Judy (See "Espionage") (Box 123)
  - Council for Social Action
  - Council on African Affairs
  - Council for Democracy
  - Counterfeiting
  - Courts
  - Couzens, James (Sen.)
  - Coyle, David Cushman
  - Co, miscellaneous
  - Con, miscellaneous (Box 124)
  - Credit unions, credit plans
  - Crime
  - Criticisms
  - Cr, miscellaneous
  - Cuba
  - Cults
  - Cummings, Homer S. (Box 125)
  - Currency
  - Czechoslovakia
  - Cu, Miscellaneous
  - Dahlberg, Edwin
  - Darrow, Clarence
  - Daughters of the American Revolution
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Literature
  - Davies, Joseph E. (Box 126)
  - Davis, Norman H.
  - D, miscellaneous
  - Day, Dorothy (See "Women")
  - Debates
  - Debts
  - Declaration of Independence
  - Defenders of Democracy, Inc.
  - Defense Committee
  - DeLucy, Hugh
  - Democracy (Box 127)
  - Democratic Party
  - Democratic Party, "The Party of Betrayal"
  - Department of Justice
    - General
    - Releases
    - Clippings (Box 128)
    - Releases
  - Descendants of American Revolution
  - Dewey, Thomas E.
  - De, Miscellaneous
  - Dickenson, Sen. Lester J.
  - Di, Miscellaneous
  - Dickstein, (Samuel) Committee (Box 129)
  - Dictatorships
  - Dilling, Elizabeth
  - Disarmament
  - Divine, Father (Box 130)
  - Doak, William N.
  - Dodd, William E. (See Also New Deal)
  - Dodd, William E. Jr. (See Also New Deal)
  - Dole
  - Dies, Bill
  - Dies, Martin
  - Dies Committee
    - General
    - Opposition (Box 131)
    - Commendation
    - Testimony
    - Clippings
    - Miscellaneous
    - Communist leaders
    - Investigation of Communism
    - Investigation of Nazism
    - Investigation of Silver Shirts
    - New Deal
    - Reports (Box 132)
    - Matthews' testimony
    - Subversive activities in Hollywood
    - Testimony, Earl Browder
    - Testimony, Ben Gitlow
    - Congressional comment
    - Consumers' groups
    - Witnesses
  - Dreiser, Theodore
  - Don, miscellaneous
  - Dubinsky, David
  - DuBois, Dr. W. E. B.
  - Duggan, Stephen Pierce
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - Duran, Gustavo
  - Durant, William C.
  - Du, miscellaneous
  - East and West Association, The (Box 133)
  - Economics
  - Economic League, The
  - Economists
  - Ecuador
  - Education
  - Education, Congressional Action, pamphlets (Box 134)
  - Eddy, Sherwood
  - Educational Alliance
  - Edutravel
  - Egypt
  - Einstein, Albert [2 folders]
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box 135)
    - General
    - Speeches
  - Eisenhower Administration
  - E, miscellaneous [2 folders]
  - Elections
    - Results (Box 136)
    - General
    - Presidential vote
    - Statistics
      - General
      - Correspondence
    - Candidates
  - Embargoes [2 folders] (Box 137)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief
  - Engdahl, J. Louis
  - Engineers to Russia
  - Ernst, Morris L.
  - Espionage
    - General
    - General [2 folders] (Box 138)
    - Remington, William W. (See New Deal)
    - Coplon Case
  - Eugenics Publishing
  - Europe
  - European Federation
  - Evolution
  - Er, miscellaneous
  - Fabian Society
  - Facts on File
  - Fadiman, Clifton
  - Falange (Box 139)
  - FEPC (Fair Employment Practices Committee)
  - Farmers' Organizations
    - General
    - Farmers' Holiday Association
    - Farmers' Independent Council of Ameria
    - Farmer Labor Party
    - Farmer Labor Political Federation. (See also Farmer Labor Party)
    - Farmers' National Relief Conference
    - National Farmers' Union
    - National Farmers' Union (Box 140)
    - Southern Tenant Farmers' Union
    - United Farmers' League
    - Farmers' Organizations - Literature
  - Fascism
  - Fascism, Gen. George Moseley (Box 141)
  - Fast, Howard
  - Faubus, Orval
  - Fay, Frank
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation
  - Federal Communications Commission
  - Federal Grand Jury Association
  - Federated Press
  - Federation of Children's Organizations
  - Fellowship of Faiths
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation [2 folders]
  - Federal Council of Chruches (Box 142)
    - General [2 folders]
    - General [2 folders] (Box 143)
    - Clippings
    - Letters and releases (Box 144)
    - Literature
    - Henry B. Joy
  - Federal Power Commission
  - Fellowship of Socialist Christians
  - Feuchtwanger, Lion
  - F, Miscellaneous (Box 145)
  - Fifth column
  - Fifth column literature
  - Fight for Freedom Committee (Box 146)
  - Filene, Edward A.
  - Films
  - Finance
  - Finland
  - Fish, Hamilton
  - Fish (Hamilton) Committee
  - Fish Committee Index
  - Flag (Box 147)
  - Flag, literature
  - Flury, Henry
  - Flynn, John T.
  - Ford, Henry
  - Fi, miscellaneous
  - Foreign agents
  - Foreign agents, Secretary of State Lists [2 folders] (Box 148)
  - Foreign investments
  - Foreign Language Information Service
  - Foreign Literature
  - Foreign Loans
  - Foreign Policy
  - Foreign Policy Association
  - Foreign Policy Association literature (Box 149)
  - Foreign Trade
    - General
    - 1958
    - 1958 (Box 150)
  - Forums
  - Fo, miscellaneous [2 folders]
  - Foundations (Box 151)
    - General
      - General
      - A-L
      - M-Z
    - Literature [2 folders] (Box 152)
    - American Foundation
    - American Memorial Foundation, Inc.
    - Carl Schurz Memorial Foundation
    - Carnegie Foundation
    - DeMille Foundation for Political Freedom
    - Foundation for Economic Education (Box 153)
    - Foundation for Religious Action in the Social and Civil Order
    - Ford Foundation, literature
      - General
      - Literature
    - Ford Foundation, literature (Box 154)
    - Henry George Foundation
    - Great Books Foundation
    - Loyal Legion Foundation
    - Lyme Foundation, Inc.
    - Robert Marshall Foundation
    - Julius Rosenwald Fund
    - National Home and Property Owners' Foundation
    - Guggenheim Foundation
    - Golden Rule Foundation
    - Rockefeller Foundation
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 155)
    - Russell Sage Foundation
      - General
      - Literature
    - National Religion and Labor Foundation
    - Robert Schalkenbach Foundation
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation
    - Four Way Movement
    - Twentieth Century Fund
    - American Heritage Foundation
    - American Progress Foundation
    - Maurice and Laura Falk Foundation
    - Foundation to Defeat Communism
    - Sidney Hillman Foundation (Box 156)
    - Independence Foundation
    - National Science Foundation [2 folders]
    - Republican Educational Foundation
    - Tax Foundation, Inc.
    - Tolstoy Foundation, Inc.
    - The Heritage American Foundation
    - Constitution and Free Enterprise Foundation
    - Freedom Foundation, Inc. (Box 157)
    - W. K. Kellogg Foundation
    - Alfred Sloan Foundation
  - France
  - Frank, Glenn (Box 158)
  - Frank, Waldo
  - Frankfurter, Felix
  - Franklin, Jay
  - Free Company
  - Free Speech and Free Press
  - Free World Association
  - Freedom House
  - Freedom of Seas
  - Freethinkers of America and Freethought Press Association [same folder]
  - Friday Magazine (Box 159)
  - Friends of Progress
  - Friends, Religious Society of
  - Friends of Democracy [5 folders]
  - Friends of Democracy [3 folders] (Box 160)
  - Friends of Soviet Union (National Council of American Soviet Friendship, Inc., Congress of American-Soviet Friendship, American Council of Soviet Relations)
  - Friends of Soviet Union [3 folders] (Box 161)
  - Friends of Soviet Union (Box 162)
  - Fr, miscellaneous [2 folders]
  - Gale, Linn A.E. (Box 163)
  - Gale, Zona
  - Gandhi
  - Garner, John Nance
  - Gastonia
  - G, miscellaneous
  - General Welfare Federation of America
  - Germany
    - General
    - Government
    - Hitler
    - Anti-Communist Drive (Box 164)
    - Anti-Semitic
    - Armaments
    - Economy
    - Finance
    - Foreign Affairs
    - Reichstag Trial
    - Pamphlets
  - Ge, miscellaneous (Box 165)
  - Gi, miscellaneous
    - General
    - Pamphlets
  - Gold and silver
  - Gordin, Morris
  - Government
    - General
    - Pamphlets
  - G.P.U.
  - Go, miscellaneous (Box 166)
  - Graham, Marcus
  - Greater New York Emergency Conference on Inalienable Rights
  - Greece
  - Greek-American Labor Committee
  - Green International
  - Greenspun, Herman
  - Griffin, Bill
  - Gr, miscellaneous
  - Government ownership
    - General
    - Clippings (Box 167)
    - Literature
    - Literature (Box 168)
  - Great Britain
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Armaments
    - Beverage Plan
    - Socialism and Communism
    - Economics (Box 169)
    - Finance
    - Foreign Relations
    - Government
    - India
    - Labor
    - Astor, Lady
    - Halifax, Lord
    - Post-war planning
    - Remarks of J. Thorkelson (Congressional Record)
    - Soviet Relations
    - World War II
    - United States
  - Hadley, Edwin M.
  - Haldeman, Julius (Box 170)
    - Literature
    - Publications
    - American Freeman (Box 171)
  - Hall, Martin
  - Hall, Gordon
  - H, miscellaneous
  - Hapgood, Powers and Mary
  - Harlan and Bell Counties
  - Han miscellaneous
  - Has, miscellaneous
  - Hayes, Carleton J.H.
  - Hays, Arthur Garfield (Box 172)
  - Hearst, William R.
  - He, miscellaneous
  - Hen, miscellaneous
  - High, Stanley
  - Hiram House
  - Hiss (See "Espionage")
  - Hillman, Sidney
  - History
    - General
    - Pamphlets
  - Hi, miscellaneous (Box 173)
  - Ho, miscellaneous
  - Hoover, Herbert [2 folders]
  - Hon, miscellaneous
  - House Un-American Activities Committee (Velde)
  - Humphrey, Hubert (Box 174)
  - Hungary
  - Hu, miscellaneous
  - Immigration
  - Immigration (Box 175)
  - Immigration legislation
  - Independent Citizens Committee of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions, Inc.
    - General
    - Committee for Medical Freedom
    - Hollywood
    - National Council
    - National Wartime Conference, Independent Voters Committee, Nonpartisan Committee of The Artists and Sciences for Roosevelt
    - Scientific and Cultural Conference for World Peace
  - Independent Coalition of American Women (Box 176)
  - Independent Progressive Party
    - General
    - California Petition Signers
  - India
  - India Independence League
  - India League of America
  - Indians
    - General
    - General (Box 177)
    - Pamphlets
  - Industrial Defense Association
  - I.W.W. [2 folders]
  - Industry
  - Inflation
  - Ingvoldstadt, Fred W.
  - Institute of International Education
  - Institutes [2 folders] (Box 178)
  - Institute for American Democracy (Christian Institute for American Democracy)
  - Institute of International Relations
  - Institute of Pacific Relations
  - Institute of Public Affairs [2 folders] (Box 179)
  - Institute of Politics
  - Institutes, Summer
  - Institute for Propaganda Analysis, Inc.
  - Institute on World Organization
  - Insurance
  - Inter-American Confederation of Workers and International Association of Revolutionary Writers [same folder]
  - International Movements
  - Internationalism [2 folders]
  - International Banking (Box 180)
  - International Chamber of Commerce
  - International Committee for Political Prisoners
  - International Council of Religious Education
  - International Entente Against the Third International
  - International Juridical Association
  - International Labor Defense
    - General
    - General [2 folders] (Box 181)
    - Labor Defender
  - International Labor Organization
  - International Council of Christian Churches
  - International Latex Corporation (Box 182)
  - International Legion Against Communism
  - International Longshoremen's Association
  - International Rescue Committee
  - International Reform Federation
  - International Trade Organization
  - International Workers Aid
  - International Workers Order
    - General
    - Literature
    - Photostats (Box 183)
    - Daily Worker References [same folder]
  - Intourist
  - Iran
  - Ireland
  - Isolationism
  - Isaacs, Stanley M.
  - Italian-American Labor Council
  - Italy (Box 184)
    - General
    - Mussolini
  - International miscellaneous
  - I clippings
    - Pamphlets (Box 185)
  - Japan
    - General
    - Pamphlets
  - Japanese-American Citizens League
  - Japanese-American Committee for Democracy
  - Jehovah's Witnesses
    - General
    - Rutherford, Judge
    - General (Box 186)
  - Jefferson, Thomas
  - J, miscellaneous
  - John Reed Club
  - Johnson, Hiram
  - Johnson, Mordecai W.
  - Jugoslavia
  - Jung, Harry
  - Jo, miscellaneous
  - Kagawa, Toyohiko (Box 187)
  - Kahn, Albert E.
  - Kaltenborn, H. V.
  - Karolyi, Michael
  - Kaspar, (Frederick) John Jr. (White Citizens Council)
  - K, miscellaneous
  - Kelley, Florence and Nicholas (Son)
  - Keller, Kent E.
  - Kellogg, Frank B.
  - Kellogg Pact
  - Kelley, Florence
  - Kerensky, Alexander
  - Key Men of America [2 folders]
  - Ke, miscellaneous (Box 188)
  - Kingdon, Dr. Frank
  - Ki, miscellaneous
  - Kl, miscellaneous
  - Knickerbocker, H. R.
  - Knights of Columbus
  - Ku Klux Klan
  - Ku, miscellaneous (Box 189)
  - Labor
    - General
    - Pamphlets
  - Labor unions (Box 190)
    - General
    - Amalgamated Clothing Workers
    - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
    - International Typo-Union (Box 191)
  - Labor Age
  - Labor injunctions
  - Labor legislation
  - Labor wage and hour laws
  - Labor Poets of America
  - Jews
    - 1927-1931
    - 1932
    - 1933
    - 1934
    - 1935
    - 1936
    - 1937 (Box 192)
    - 1938
    - 1939
    - 1940
    - 1941-1942
    - 1942-1948 (Box 193)
    - Anti-Nazi Movement
    - British Policy in Palestine
    - Israel, Rabbi Edward L.
    - Sapior, Aaron
    - Untermyer, Samuel
    - Drive to Combat Anti-Semitism
    - Financial
    - Articles
    - Pamphlets [3 folders] (Box 194)
    - Edmondson, literature (Box 195)
    - Anti-Semitism [2 folders]
  - Jews in other countries (Box 196)
    - Austria
    - Germany
    - Palestine
    - Rumania (Box 197)
    - France
    - Italy
    - Poland
    - Russia
  - Jewish organizations
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Women
    - American Jewish Committee
    - American Jewish Congress
    - American Anti-Defamation League of B'nai Brith (Box 198)
    - Jewish B. Brith
    - American Council for Judaism, Inc.
    - American League for a Free Palestine, Inc.
    - American Zionist Emergency Council
    - Committee for a Jewish Army of Stateless and Palestinian Jews
    - Emergency Committee to Save the Jewish People of Europe
    - ICOR
    - Jewish Labor Committee
    - Jewish People's Committee
    - Jewish War Vets
    - National Pilgrimage to Save Jewish States
    - National Council of Jewish Women
    - ORT
    - Jewish Palestine Homeland Movement
    - Jewish protocols
    - Jewish refugees
    - Jewish relief
    - Protocols of Elders of Zion. (See Jewish Protocols)
    - World Jewish Congress (Box 199)
    - Zionist Movement
    - Wise, Dr. Stephen S.
  - Jewish pamphlets and literature
  - Jewish pamphlets and literature [2 folders] (Box 200)
  - L, miscellaneous (Box 201)
  - Labor's Non-Partisan League [2 folders]
  - La Follettes, miscellaneous
  - La Follette, committee
  - La Follette, Philip F.
  - La Follette, Robert M.
  - La Guardia, F. H. (Box 202)
  - Laidler, Harry
  - Lamont, Thomas and Corliss
  - Landon, Alfred
  - Laski, Harold J.
  - Latin America
  - Laubach, Frank C.
  - Lar, miscellaneous
  - League for Constitutional Government (Box 203)
  - League for Independent Political Action
    - General
    - Literature
  - League for Mutual Aid
  - League for Organization of Progress
  - League for Political Education
  - League of American Writers
  - Lee, Ivy
  - Legislation [2 folders]
  - Legislation, radical
  - Lehman, Herbert H.
  - Leisure League of America, Inc.
  - Len, miscellaneous (Box 204)
  - Lerner, Max
  - Lewis, Sinclair
  - Li, miscellaneous
  - Libby, Dr. Fred J. (Box 205)
  - Liberalism
  - Liberia
  - Liberty Party
  - Lilienthal, David Eli
  - Lincoln, Abraham
    - General
    - Pamphlets
  - Lindbergh, Charles A.
  - Lindsey, Judge Ben
  - League for Industrial Democracy (Box 206)
    - General
      - General
      - Letterheads
      - Pamphlets
      - Pamphlets [2 folders] (Box 207)
      - Releases (Box 208)
      - Clippings
    - Knoxville Publishing Company, vs.
  - League of Nations
    - General
      - 1930
      - 1931
      - 1932
      - 1933
      - 1934
      - 1935
      - General [2 folders] (Box 209)
    - Clippings
  - League of Nations Association
  - League of Nations (Box 210)
  - Lobby, lobbying
  - Lockwood, Geo. B. Articles
  - Logan Act
  - Long, Huey
  - Lorwin, Lewis L. (Box 211)
  - Lovett, Robert Morris
  - Loyalty, loyalty oath
  - Lubin, Isador (Dr.)
  - Ludecke, Kurt G. W.
  - Ludwig, Emil
  - Lusk Report
  - Lyons, Eugene
  - L, miscellaneous
  - L, miscellaneous (Box 212)
  - M, miscellaneous
  - MacArthur, Gen. Douglas
  - MacDonald, J. Ramsay
  - Machine Age
  - Manchuria
  - Mankind United
  - Mantle Club
  - Marcantonio, Vito (Box 213)
  - Marches and riots
  - Marine Corps
  - Marine workers
  - Marsh, Ben C.
  - Morley, Lord Dudley
  - Martens, Ludwig C.A.K.
  - Marx, Karl and Friedrich Engels
  - Marvin, Fred
  - Masons (Box 214)
  - Match industry
  - Mauldin, William
  - Maverick, Maury
  - Matusow, Harvey M.
  - Maurer, James H.
  - Map, miscellaneous
  - McAdoo, William G.
  - McCarthy, Joseph
  - McCarthy, Aides
  - McCarthy censure
  - McCarthy opposition (Box 215)
  - McCarthy press
  - McCarthy - Wechsler
  - McFadden, Louis T.
  - McNutt, Paul V.
  - McC, miscellaneous
  - McD, miscellaneous
  - McH, miscellaneous
  - McN, miscellaneous
  - Means, Gaston B.
  - Medicine
  - Mellon, Andrew W.
  - Mencken, Henry L.
  - Merchant Marine
  - Mexico
  - Mexico (Box 216)
  - Meyer, Eugene and Mrs.
  - Me, miscellaneous
  - Military Order of World War
  - Military Training
  - Military Training (Box 217)
  - Mi, miscellaneous
  - Milwaukee
  - Modernism
  - Moley, Raymond C.
  - Monetary
  - Monroe Doctrine (Box 218)
  - Mooney-Billings Case
    - General
    - Releases
  - Morgan, J. P.
  - Morrow, Dwight W.
  - Morse, Wayne (Box 219)
  - Mortgage refinancing
  - Moseley, George Van Horn (Gen.)